# **Dmitry Sakhatarov**

Moscow, Moscow City, Russia



dmitris94@mail.ru



+79142832508



linkedin.com/in/dmitry-sakhatarov

# **Summary**

I am a professional analyst with over 5 years of experience in Mining Industry.

Graduated from Mining University as Mining Engineer, I discovered an interest in analytics and wanted to use my skills in this area. I am building a successful career and practically applying my skills and abilities, developing as a professional, learning new things.

My strengths: leadership, team player, customer oriented, purposeful, high-performing, permanent learner, stress-resistant, ability to solve problems.

Proficient:

Programming languages: Microsoft PowerBi, MySQL, SQL, Microsoft Office (Excel advanced), Tableau, R-studio and Python basics.

Additional programm languages and tools: XPath, HTML5, SeleniumIDE, Chrome Dev tools, Notepad++ Bug tracking tools: Jira, Confluence, Zendesk

# **Experience**

# Performance Assurance Supervisor (Customer Success)

Komatsu Mining

Dec 2021 - Present (4 months +)

Manage a team tasked with enhancing and sustaining the customer experience within the Eurasia region. Team focus on ensuring our customers have the support and guidance to best utilize their investment in Modular products and services. Data driven results that showcase outcomes and identify opportunities for continuous improvement. Details:

- Supervision of the work team in the area of Continuous Improvement
- Generation of opportunities for improvement with Clients through constant monitoring of operating accounts
- Resource management to carry out continuous improvement cycles
- Participation in initiatives / meetings with different areas of the Komatsu group
- Synergy between Corporate regions
- Supervision of Company Training personnel

# Performance Assurance Specialist (Analytics)

Komatsu Mining

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021 (7 months)

- -Collaboration with the Hardware and Software Engineers during the deployment stage
- -Providing a Performance Assurance Assessment prior to the deployment to evaluate all possible risks and create a roadmap for a successful system adoption
- -Knowledge exchange between the regions and training/consulting for the local team
- -Meeting with the customers, data analysis, planning, and conducting scheduled visits.

### Performance Assurance Engineer (Analytics)

#### Komatsu Mining

Jul 2019 - Jun 2021 (2 years)

Daily data modeling and data analysis of mining KPIs to identify mining improvement and cost reduction opportunities.

Using data analysis to engage with the customers and support the improvement projects to ensure they receive the best possible value from the products and achieve continual improvement of system functionality and performance.

As a field service engineer, providing site visits, data analysis/reporting, generating and creating key performance indicators for the Performance Assurance Process.

## Mining Engineer

Mechel

Jul 2017 - Apr 2019 (1 year 10 months)

Working in a production department. Analysis of technical and economic indicators of the mine-transport complex of the mine; Preparation of applications, documents, reports, orders, etc.; Control over mining, overburden operations, transportation of rock mass, and coal products. Development of regulatory documents, technical and contractual documentation; Analysis of daily operational records of production indicators, the implementation of daily and shift plans. Timely and accurate introduction of shift information on mining and transport equipment and production indicators in the information base of 1C "Production"

## Mining Engineer

Mechel

Apr 2017 - Jul 2017 (4 months)

Working in a maintenance department. Analysis of technical and economic indicators of the mine-transport complex of the mine; Preparation of applications, documents, reports, orders, etc.; The study and analysis of the causes of downtime technological vehicles. Accounting of knots and units.

#### **Education**



\delta National mineral resources university (University of mines)

Master's degree in Mining, Mining and Mineral Engineering 2011 - 2017

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- 20778AC: Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Microsoft Power BI Microsoft
- 20761C: Querying Data with Transact-SQL Microsoft
- **Power BI and Excel advanced level: DAX and Power Query** Нетология

#### **Skills**

Data Analysis • Process Engineering • Mining Engineering • Mining • Analytical Skills • Analytics • Coal • Business Intelligence (BI) • Statistics • Operations Management